

Elian Abboud

Nationality: Syrian Date of birth: 08/03/2001 Gender: Male

Compared to the compared t

github: https://github.com/Elian-abboud **Skype:** live:.cid.a17c4a0118571eb2

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/elian-abboud

Website: https://elian-abboud.github.io/Responsive Portfolio/

• Home: Abboud Building, Broad Street , Dwellaa , DAMASCUS (Syria)

ABOUT ME

-Bachelor's Degree in "Informatics Engineering"

-with experience in Web Development by (HTML, CSS, JS),

- -and experience in Mobile Application Development by (Flutter & Dart)
- -also, I have acquired proficient programming skills in C# and Python.

-Over the course of more than three years, I have gained valuable experience in IT Support through my tenure at both the Melkite Greek Catholic Patriarchate and Francis-tech company. During this time, I successfully resolved a wide range of technical issues, demonstrating my ability to handle diverse technical challenges effectively..

WORK EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Specialist

Melkite Greek catholic patriarchate (Full time) [04/2022 - Current]

City: Damascus **Country:** Syria

- 1 System Administrator
- 2 Database Administrator

3 -in addition to Provide technical assistance to computer users. Answer questions and resolve computer problems for clients in person, via telephone, or electronically. May provide assistance concerning the use of computer hardware and software, including printing, installation, word processing, electronic mail, and operating systems.

Digital Marketing Officer

Francis-Tech [01/2023 – Current]

Country: France

- 1- Creating content, including text posts, video and images for use on social media.
- 2- Creating Posters and advertisements.
- 3- Promoting products, services and content over social media, in a way that is consistent with an organization's brand and social media strategy.
- 4- Interacting with customers and dealing with customer's enquiries.
- 5- Developing new social media strategies and campaigns.
- 6-Moderating all social media platforms including LinkedIn, Facebook

in brief responsible for driving awareness of a company's products and services via digital channels such as online advertising and social media and plan and execute digital campaigns, monitor their success and report results back to business leadership.

Junior Frontend Web Developer (internship)

Francis-Tech [07/2023 - 09/2023]

Country: France

it was a training in various areas of Front -End web Development focusing on HTML, CSS, JS

IT Support

Francis-Tech [10/2021 – Current]

Website: https://www.francis-tech.com/ Email address: info@francis-tech.com

Name of unit or department: Software Development - Business or sector: Information and communication

- Main duties are to Provide IT related support to all customers in Syria after service delivery, Provide technical assistance to customers in addition to Answer questions and resolve the problems for clients remotely or on-site

IT Support

Freelancer [12/2019 - 11/2023]

City: Damascus **Country:** Syria

Providing the following services to organizations, institutions and individuals:

- Installation OS and applying necessary configurations when needed
- Troubleshooting & resolving issues occurred in operating software or hardware, and ensuring the installation of proper updates
- Providing remote on-call supports to customers reporting any type of technical problems.
- Providing technology consulting

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor's Degree, Informatics Engineering

International University of Science and Technology (IUST) [10/2019 - 06/2024]

Address: Ghabagheb-Daraa highway ,SYRIA, Fax: +963 15 68691974

Website: http://iust.edu.sy/en/

High school (Scientific Branch)

Ministry of Education in the Syrian Arab Republic [2019]

City: Damascus, Country: Syria Final grade: 73%

CompTIA A+

participation certificate "Institute CCIT SYRIA" sponsored (GOPA-DERD & UNHCR) [12/2019]

Introduction to Python

SoloLearn Platform [10/2023]

Principles of UX/UI Design

Coursera | **Meta** [10/2023]

HTML and CSS in Depth

Coursera | Meta [09/2023]

Version Control

Coursera | Meta [08/2023]

Al For Everyone

Coursera | DeepLearning.AI [07/2023]

Introduction to Front-End Development

Coursera | **Meta** [07/2023]

Programming with JavaScript

Coursera | Meta [07/2023]

Introduction to JavaScript

SoloLearn Platform [06/2023]

Introduction to CSS

SoloLearn Platform [05/2023]

Introduction to HTML

SoloLearn Platform [05/2023]

Web Development Fundamentals

SoloLearn Platform [04/2023]

Digital Marketing Fundamentals

Google [03/2023]

SQL Intermediate

SoloLearn Platform [03/2023]

The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking

Coursera | Google [02/2023]

Dart: Variables, Data Structures, Objects, and Conditionals

Coursera [09/2022]

introduction to Dart

Coursera [09/2022]

Getting started with Flutter Development

Coursera [07/2022]

Python for Beginners

SoloLearn Platform [03/2022]

Create a professional LinkedIn Profile

Coursera [12/2021]

Introduction to Relational Database and SQL

Coursera [11/2021]

Technical Support Fundamentals

Coursera | Google [11/2021]

C#

SoloLearn Platform [10/2021]

SQL

SoloLearn Platform [10/2021]

How to Create and Style an Artboard in Adobe XD

Coursera [09/2021]

Create and design databases using MYSQL Workbench

Coursera [05/2021]

Write Professional Emails in English

Coursera | Georgia Institute of Technology [09/2021]

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Arabic

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Troubleshooting / Software Development / Web Development / HTML / CSS / JavaScript / Mobile Application Development / Flutter / Dart / Figma / UI /UX Design / Python / C# / SQI / Database Management System (DBMS) / Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) / Digital Marketing / IT Infrastructure Management / IT Service Management / CompTIA A+ / IDE: Visual Studio, VSCode, Android Studio. / Communication Skills

PROJECTS

Mobile application to provide services to IUST University students (Graduation Project)

[11/2023 - Current]

The "IUST App" mobile app supports Arabic and English also Dark and Light mode for App is tailored for students at the International University of Science and Technology. This app streamlines the academic experience, offering features such as:

- University news
- Ads
- Document requests
- GPA calculation
- course planning
- communication information with the university & Map.
- personalized QR code for student identification and easy access to Personal information.
- · Send marks as notifications:

This app simplifies student life, promoting convenience and efficiency in university-related tasks and communication

The platform used on this app: Flutter, Dart, Firebase

Personal Responsive Portfolio Website

[07/2023 - 07/2023]

Write here the description...HTML,CSS,I

- 1- Personal Responsive Portfolio Website
- 2-Smooth scrolling in each section.
- 3-Includes a light and dark mode.
- 4-Compatible with all mobile devices and with a beautiful and pleasant user interface.
- 5- Contain many section: Home, About, Skills, Services, Portfolio, Contact

Link: https://elian-abboud.github.io/Responsive_Portfolio/

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer at (Saint Joseph's Church)

[Syria - Damascus , 02/2023 - 03/2023]

Equipping shelters for those affected by the earthquake that occurred in Syria on February 6, by providing accommodation, preparing foodstuffs and personal supplies, Delivering relief materials and coordinating activities for children's entertainment and psychological support for those affected by the earthquake.

Volunteering was through the Christian Youth Team at St. Joseph Church

Community Volunteer at "Syrian Social Nationalist Party (SSNP)"

[Syria - Damascus, 01/2016 - 2018]

- implemented social activities such as beautifying and restoration the city squares.
- implemented afforestation campaigns
- assisting in coordinating and planning activities, travel programs, and camps.

All of the above was done by a team called the Youth Team

Volunteering was 3 hours a day, 3 days a week, for 3 years